# **Brian Khoo - Software Engineer**

415-819-7126 • khoo.brian123@gmail.com • GitHub • LinkedIn • Portfolio URL

## SKILLS

Languages: Javascript, Typescript, Python, Ruby, Java, HTML, CSS, SQL

Frameworks & Libraries: React, Redux, Flask, Express.js, SQLAlchemy, Sequelize, PostgreSQL, Next.js, MongoDB, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, Axios, ReactChart.js, Prisma.io, Ruby on Rails, Material UI

# **PROJECTS**

Bootcamp Brokers GitHub | Live Site

Group Project: Fullstack financial investment app enabling users to buy and sell financial products built on React.js, Javascript, Python, Redux, Flask

- Integrated Financial API's for real-time stock data, providing an immersive financial trading experience.
- Implemented data visualizations for engaging portfolio visualizations and simplified investment analysis.
- Created a context aware chatbot utilizing Open Al's Chat GPT 3.5-Turbo API to assist users

AirBK GitHub | Live Site

Fullstack Travel / Home Rental website built on React, Typescript, Tailwind CSS, Next.js, MongoDB

- Created a seamless UI/UX design to ensure an intuitive and user-friendly browsing and booking experience.
- Implemented a dynamic React Calendar for intuitive date selection, facilitating seamless booking of locations.

Aldea GitHub | Live Site

Fullstack AI Productivity Workspace Website built on React, Python, Chat GPT 3.5 Turbo API, Flask, Redux

- Utilized prompt engineering techniques to create AI Tools that would ease the users workflow
- Developed a Quill.js rich text editor for note-taking, incorporating AI assistance to optimize users' workspace.
- Created rich and immersive UI features allowing the user to organize their workspaces and notes.

### EXPERIENCE

#### **Software Engineer Intern**

Rubbish June 2023 - Present

Developing geolocating software and data visualization tools to help cities clean up trash, plastic, and graffiti.

### **Software Engineer Intern**

ChirrUp May 2023 - Present

# **Frontend Developer**

Stealth Startup May 2023 - Present

Contributed to developing a web platform connecting research initiatives with venture capital.

## **Lead Operations Associate**

JP Morgan Chase Aug 2020 - Oct 2022

- Oversaw daily branch operations overseeing cash entities, employee schedules and customer satisfaction
- Managed a team of 15 spearheading process optimization strategies enhancing operational efficiency

### **Small Business Owner**

Import Export Business Feb 2017 - Feb 2022

- Operated an import export business identifying market opportunities for growth and sales
- Conducted market research to identify in-demand products, optimizing offerings for targeted customer segments

#### **Production Associate**

Charlotte Russe Jul 2015 - Oct 2017

- Strategically managed inventory schedules by analyzing supply and demand trends
- Implemented rigorous quality assurance tests on products, meticulously verifying compliance

### **EDUCATION**

**App Academy -** Full Stack Software Engineering Program **Southern New Hampshire University -** Bachelor of Science in Finance